# Maheshchandra Hegde

Lead User Interface Developer and a UX Designer

(91) 9535253329, 7022407280 hid.mahesh@gmail.com

#### **OVERVIEW**

A passionate Developer and Designer having more than 12 years of expertise over UI technologies like HTML, Javascript, CSS, Flex and ActionScript.

Completed Masters in Advanced Computing (Full-time, in Campus) (Specialization: Human Interface Design and Development) from 'The Robert Gordon University', Scotland, United Kingdom.

Skilled in rapid designing, prototyping and bootstrapping Angular, Flex and other UI applications.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **UST Global**, Bangalore — Associate Project Manager

APRIL 2018 - FEB 2019

Lead a UI team to successfully kickstart/complete multiple UI projects.

## **UST Global**, Bangalore — Senior Systems Analyst

FEB 2015 - MARCH 2018

Worked as a senior resource and handled multiple UI development projects.

## ThoughtFocus, Bangalore — UI /UX Tech Lead

OCT 2011 - MARCH 2014 - (SEP 2012 - MARCH 2014 UX/UI Lead/Architect, OCT 2011 - APRIL 2012 as Adobe Flex Consultant)

Prototyped, designed and developed application using HTML,CSS,Adobe Flex and Flash . Established a successful process of involving users early in to the design process by mockups and prototypes before actually delivering the product.

### **InnoBrik**, Bangalore — Co-Founder

FEB 2011 - JAN 2015

Co-Founded and held multiple lead technical roles in the startup.

#### STRENGTHS INCLUDE

Rapid prototyping and bootstrapping UI.

Creative Individual having Strong Designing and 3d modeling skills.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular 2 to 6, AngularJS, NodeJS, Bootstrap, Adobe Flex, Photoshop, 3ds Max, CAD and other design and development tools

#### **EDUCATION**

Robert Gordon University Scotland, United Kingdom — MS in Computing

SEP 2005 - DEC 2006

Bapuji Institute of Engineering & Technology, Davanagere — Bachelor of Engineering(E&C)

JULY 1999 - APR 2003

# **Independent Consultant**, Bangalore — User Experience Designer and Adobe Flex Developer

DEC 2010 - FEB 2011

Worked as an independent consultant to companies like DGLogik, CISCO, Vodafone, ThoughtFocus to complete multiple Adobe Flex design/development project assignments successfully.

## **Cisco Systems India Private Limited,** Bangalore — *Independent Consultant*

MAY 2009 - NOV 2010

Designed and developed 'Facility Dashboard' at CISCO using Adobe Flex and Flash.

## **Freelance Web Developer**, Bangalore —worked as an *Independent Consultant*

APR 2008 - APR 2009

Web designing and development, Development of Rich Internet Applications, Architectural visualization, 3d modeling, 3d walkthroughs, CAD.

# **CAE Simulation Technologies,** Bangalore —Visual Database Developer

SEP 2007 - APR 2008

Worked on 3d modelling for Military and Civil Aircraft Simulators.(CAE stands for Canadian Aeronautical Engineering Company).

## Cognizant, Chennai — Programmer Analyst Trainee

APR 2004 - DEC 2004

Part of a Support team for a project called DUNSLINK. Worked on DB2, COBOL and Mainframes.